<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Aswin's blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Aswin's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes after working at a 14-people startup</title><link>/blog/notes-after-working-at-a-startup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/notes-after-working-at-a-startup/</guid><description>Notes after working at a 14-people startup I worked at Subconscious Compute—a toddler of a startup at Bengaluru for 5 months—and I know I can write this post in two ways: like a typical Glassdoor review of the company, or like one of my usual blog posts – a candor walk-through of something that was new to me with some gratitude towards the end.
From day one, I wanted to write this blog down with every detail, and make it as fun and artistic as the public image of the company on LinkedIn.</description></item><item><title>Notes from Israel</title><link>/blog/notes-from-israel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/notes-from-israel/</guid><description>These are the candid, first-hand writings of my trip to Israel to attend a summer school on ‘Data Mining and Cybersecurity for Business Intelligence’ at the Ben-Gurion University in July 2022. The prose is mostly first-person and like a diary entry.
Since I wrote things on the fly and added things later, I’m also sure the grammar isn’t perfect and I switch tenses here and there. These were mostly written for myself and probably lack context at multiple places.</description></item><item><title>Hello OpenBSD</title><link>/blog/hello-openbsd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/hello-openbsd/</guid><description>Oh, hi!
This is a blog post about the things I stumbled upon when I thought I&amp;rsquo;ll give OpenBSD a go. Therefore, this post is going to sound more like a walkthrough than an ordinary blog post.
The reason why I decided to try it out was primarily for the learning experience, and to use it as a hobby OS- something you boot up every once in a while when you want to slow down and relax a bit.</description></item><item><title>Side Channel and Fault Injection Attacks with the ChipWhisperer</title><link>/blog/csaw-esc-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/csaw-esc-2021/</guid><description>Couple months ago, I had participated in the CSAW Embedded Security Challenges (ESC)- a perennial competition about security of embedded systems and devices. Each year, the competition comes with a different theme and the time around, it was about Side Channel and Fault Injection attacks with the ChipWhisperer Nano. The team and I had a fun time learning and getting used to them.
This blog is aimed at giving a short glimpse on what SCAs and other things in its realm are in a nutshell.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer Of Code 2021- Support for CPU and Platform Profiles</title><link>/blog/gsoc-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/gsoc-2021/</guid><description>Hi all,
This blog post is a brief summary about the work I did on the summer of 2021 with Rizin on adding support for CPU and platform profiles.
Title of the project Support for CPU and platform profiles
Synopsis Rizin previously relied upon manually writing code for adding a new CPU or an IO port. This implementation was unfit as the vast and growing ecology of hardware components such as CPUs and SoCs regularly implement a part of architecture with custom instructions, registers, and address configurations with trivial differences, making it infeasible to maintain all of them inside Rizin.</description></item><item><title>Preserving the commons in computing</title><link>/blog/the-commons-in-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-commons-in-computing/</guid><description>I must begin by expressing the joy that is unspeakable to be born in this era and to be using this impressive technology that is computers, to the fullest and is thankful to be able to develop software on them with the least effort and price than it was ever before. For that, I think I must heed the engineers of the past, who knew what they were doing, and to the companies for manufacturing electronics and their ideas.</description></item><item><title>CSAW Embedded Security Challenges 2020 - Quals' writeup</title><link>/blog/csaw-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/csaw-2020/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will look at reverse engineering and solving a RISC-V binary, which was the challenge for qualifying for the CSAW 2020 Embedded Security Challenge (ESC), using the reverse engineering tool Ghidra SRE​.
Ghidra SRE, out of the box, does not support analyzing binaries for the RISC-V architecture. In order to get around that, we will be setting up a special RISC-V Ghidra Processor Module. For that, we just have to clone the Module’s files into the directory named Processors of the Ghidra’s program files.</description></item><item><title>InCTF Internationals- author's writeup for Invisible Maze</title><link>/blog/inctfi-invisible-maze/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/inctfi-invisible-maze/</guid><description>For inCTF International Edition 2020, I had so much fun in making a Gameboy ROM reversing challenge.
This is the writeup for the same.
Invisible Maze tl;dr
Challenge is a Nintendo GameBoy ROM image. Reverse the ROM and figure out the implementation Analyze the calling function&amp;rsquo;s checks to find the path along which we must move. Challenge points: 936
No. of solves: 13
Challenge Authors: officialcjunior and k4iz3n</description></item><item><title>Reversing Nanomites</title><link>/blog/reversing-nanomites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/reversing-nanomites/</guid><description>One particular challenge over there rootme.org taught me a couple of things and I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be great to share some of them.
The challenge name is &amp;lsquo;ELF x64 - Nanomites - Introduction&amp;rsquo; and you can get it from here. It just asks for an input, which is the flag.
Nanomites are programs where you have two processes: a father and a son. A parent and a child, if you will.</description></item><item><title>Reversing MIPS for the first time</title><link>/blog/reversing-mips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/reversing-mips/</guid><description>Lately, I had got a reversing challenge compiled for MIPS architecture and I struggled a bit as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a lot information on the web on how to analyze or debug it properly.
The is a small writeup on how I learned about MIPS and completed the challenge.
Emulator QEMU is probably the best emulator out there and QEMU lets you emulate a MIPS Malta system
If you are on Ubuntu, you can get QEMU using aptitude</description></item><item><title>The Bus Pirate manual</title><link>/blog/the-bus-pirate-manual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-bus-pirate-manual/</guid><description>A simple manual to help you start working with your Bus Pirate.
Useful links To learn about what the device can do for you, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest starting somewhere near Sparkfun&amp;rsquo;s article or the Bus Pirate 102 manual
Flashing the firmware After connecting the Bus Pirate, and cloning the Bus Pirate repository, simply navigate to the folder package. You should know about the version of the Bus Pirate you own and navigate to the corresponding folder</description></item><item><title>Look Into The Past - Writeup from NeverlanCTF</title><link>/blog/look-into-the-past/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/look-into-the-past/</guid><description>Neverlan CTF: Look into the past We played NeverLAN CTF and had so much fun playing it.
In the Forensics section, there was this task named Look into the past, which was really fun to solve. So, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just write something about it.
You can find the challenge file here.
After taking a look at the filesystem unzipping the challenge file, it is clear that this is a snapshot of a Linux file system.</description></item><item><title>Booting up my first Raspberry Pi</title><link>/blog/booting-paspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/booting-paspberry-pi/</guid><description>Lately, I happened to lay my hands on one of the hottest topic on the tech world, the Raspberry Pi. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about it, the Raspberry Pi is a low cost, credit-card sized computer that plugs into monitor or TV, and uses a standard keyboard and mouse.
When I held the Pi in my palm, the first thing I realized is that, like a real raspberry, it was indeed, very small.</description></item><item><title/><link>/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bookshelf/</guid><description>Aswin&amp;rsquo;s bookshelf This is a list of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read and enjoyed. Inspired by Patrick Collison&amp;rsquo;s Bookshelf.
&amp;ldquo;Since the stacks and shelves lack any particular order, so too does this list.&amp;rdquo;
Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind – Yuval Noah Harari Life-altering insights about human origins, civilization, religion, empires, science, technology, and human nature.
The God of Small Things – Arundhati Roy Possibly the best English fiction with a story set in Kerala.</description></item><item><title/><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>Computer Science Talks and presentations Slides from &amp;ldquo;Summer of Code at Rizin&amp;rdquo; - a talk I gave at FOSSMEC on December 2 2022, where I talked about my Google Summer of Code project, the experience, and insights: Slides
Slides from a talk about Linux and UNIX history - an internal talk at teambi0s: Slides
Model perception in the virtual world - course project for 21ECE431-Neuroengineering: Slides
Software These are my software projects that I wrote from scratch.</description></item><item><title/><link>/tweets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tweets/</guid><description>Tweets This is a list of some of the best tweets I&amp;rsquo;ve put.
The word &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; is perhaps too feeble a term to encapsulate the breadth of ideas my tweets sometimes touch. But it&amp;rsquo;s usually a mix of wit, wisdom, and the unbridled exuberance of 3 A.M.
About terraces being a place with privacy for Indian kids: Link Advice on improving writing: Link South Indian aesthetics: Link Year end post of 2021 : Contains wishful thinking and subtly motivating words.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Aswin. I&amp;rsquo;m a 22 year old Malayali from Kerala, currently living in Bengaluru.
My most generalized philosophy of life can summed up in this:
Here are some of my interests:
Computer science: I am a Computer Science and Engineering undergraduate from Amrita University, Kollam. At my university, I was a member of a student-run computer security club at my university—teambi0s. At bi0s, I used to mentor students, manage the team, work on various projects and play CTFs.</description></item></channel></rss>