<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Aswin's blog</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Aswin's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preserving the commons in computing</title><link>/blog/the-commons-in-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-commons-in-computing/</guid><description>I must begin by expressing the joy that is unspeakable to be born in this era and to be using this impressive technology that is computers, to the fullest and is thankful to be able to develop software on them with the least effort and price than it was ever before. For that, I think I must heed the engineers of the past, who knew what they were doing, and to the companies for manufacturing electronics and their ideas.</description></item><item><title>CSAW Embedded Security Challenges 2020 - Quals' writeup</title><link>/blog/csaw-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/csaw-2020/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will look at reverse engineering and solving a RISC-V binary, which was the challenge for qualifying for the CSAW 2020 Embedded Security Challenge (ESC), using the reverse engineering tool Ghidra SRE​.
Ghidra SRE, out of the box, does not support analyzing binaries for the RISC-V architecture. In order to get around that, we will be setting up a special RISC-V Ghidra Processor Module. For that, we just have to clone the Module’s files into the directory named Processors of the Ghidra’s program files.</description></item><item><title>InCTF Internationals- author's writeup for Invisible Maze</title><link>/blog/inctfi-invisible-maze/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/inctfi-invisible-maze/</guid><description>For inCTF International Edition 2020, I had so much fun in making a Gameboy ROM reversing challenge.
This is the writeup for the same.
Invisible Maze tl;dr
Challenge is a Nintendo GameBoy ROM image. Reverse the ROM and figure out the implementation Analyze the calling function&amp;rsquo;s checks to find the path along which we must move. Challenge points: 936
No. of solves: 13
Challenge Authors: officialcjunior and k4iz3n</description></item><item><title>Reversing Nanomites</title><link>/blog/reversing-nanomites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/reversing-nanomites/</guid><description>One particular challenge over there rootme.org taught me a couple of things and I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be great to share some of them.
The challenge name is &amp;lsquo;ELF x64 - Nanomites - Introduction&amp;rsquo; and you can get it from here. It just asks for an input, which is the flag.
Nanomites are programs where you have two processes: a father and a son. A parent and a child, if you will.</description></item><item><title>Reversing MIPS for the first time</title><link>/blog/reversing-mips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/reversing-mips/</guid><description>Lately, I had got a reversing challenge compiled for MIPS architecture and I struggled a bit as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a lot information on the web on how to analyze or debug it properly.
The is a small writeup on how I learned about MIPS and completed the challenge.
Emulator QEMU is probably the best emulator out there and QEMU lets you emulate a MIPS Malta system
If you are on Ubuntu, you can get QEMU using aptitude</description></item><item><title>The Bus Pirate manual</title><link>/blog/the-bus-pirate-manual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-bus-pirate-manual/</guid><description>A simple mannual to help you start working with your Bus Pirate.
Useful links To learn about what the device can do for you, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest starting somewhere near Sparkfun&amp;rsquo;s article or the Bus Pirate 102 mannual
Flashing the firmware After connecting the Bus Pirate, and cloning the Bus Pirate repository, simply navigate to the folder package. You should know about the version of the Bus Pirate you own and navigate to the corresponding folder</description></item><item><title>Look Into The Past - Writeup from NeverlanCTF</title><link>/blog/look-into-the-past/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/look-into-the-past/</guid><description>Neverlan CTF: Look into the past We played NeverLAN CTF and had so much fun playing it.
In the Forensics section, there was this task named Look into the past, which was really fun to solve. So, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just write something about it.
You can find the challenge file here.
After taking a look at the filesystem unzipping the challenge file, it is clear that this is a snapshot of a Linux file system.</description></item><item><title>Booting up my first Raspberry Pi</title><link>/blog/booting-paspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/booting-paspberry-pi/</guid><description>Lately, I happened to lay my hands on one of the hottest topic on the tech world, the Raspberry Pi. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about it, the Raspberry Pi is a low cost, credit-card sized computer that plugs into monitor or TV, and uses a standard keyboard and mouse.
When I held the Pi in my palm, the first thing I realized is that, like a real raspberry, it was indeed, very small.</description></item></channel></rss>